liftopia.com 2014-12-17

# Liftopia - Privacy Statement

Last revised on September 1, 2013

We at Liftopia, Inc. (Liftopia) are committed to protecting your privacy and creating a safe and secure online environment for anyone who visits and books on our website, located at [www.liftopia.com](http://www.liftopia.com/) (the “Site”). This privacy statement discloses the privacy practices for our Site.

By submitting “Personally Identifiable Information” (information that allows someone to identify or contact you, as well as any other non-public information about you that is associated with or linked to any of the foregoing information) through our Site, you agree to the terms of this Privacy Statement and you expressly consent to the collection, use and disclosure or your Personally Identifiable Information in accordance with this Privacy Statement. Your trust and confidence are our highest priority. For questions or concerns regarding our Privacy Statement, please contact Liftopia at (800) 349-0870.

#### TRUSTe Program

Liftopia, Inc. has been awarded TRUSTe's Privacy Seal signifying that this privacy policy and practices have been reviewed by TRUSTe for compliance with [TRUSTe's program requirements](http://www.truste.com/privacy-program-requirements/) including transparency, accountability and choice regarding the collection and use of your personal information. TRUSTe's mission, as an independent third party, is to accelerate online trust among consumers and organizations globally through its leading privacy trustmark and innovative trust solutions. If you have questions or complaints regarding our privacy policy or practices, please contact us at [support@liftopia.com](mailto:support@liftopia.com). If you are not satisfied with our response you can contact [TRUSTe here](https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request). The TRUSTe program covers only information that is collected through this Web site and Liftopia mobile app.

Liftopia, Inc. complies with the U.S. – E.U. Safe Harbor framework and the U.S. – Swiss Safe Harbor framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal data from European Union member countries and Switzerland. Liftopia, Inc. has certified that it adheres to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement. To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, and to view Liftopia, Inc. ‘s certification, please visit http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/.

#### What information we collect from you

In order to make a purchase and use certain services on this Site, you must first register for an account to log in to our network (“Account”). When you register with Liftopia, we ask for Personally Identifiable Information, including your first and last name, e-mail address and password. We retain information on your behalf, such as itineraries or other files that you store using your Account.

When you place an order for lift tickets, rentals, lessons or other products, we request certain Personally Identifiable Information from you on our order form. You must provide contact information (such as first and last name, e-mail, and billing address) and financial information (such as credit card number, expiration date and security code). We use this information for billing purposes and to complete the transaction. If we have trouble processing an order, we will use this information to contact you.

When you download and use our Services, we automatically collect information on the type of device you use, operating system version, and the device identifier (or "UDID"). We collect your location based information for the purpose of locating a ski resorts that you may be searching for in your area. We will only share this information with our mapping provider for the sole purpose of providing you this service.

For all Liftopia visitors -- not just registered users – our servers collect Personally Identifiable Information, such as IP addresses, browser type, domain names, operating system, access times, duration of visit, referring URL, platform, new/repeat information, timestamp and exit page information. We gather this information to analyze trends and performances over time to make our Site and services more useful to you and. Liftopia uses third-party service providers to help us gather and analyze information about our customers. These service providers are contractually restricted from using your information in any manner other than in helping us to provide you with the products and services available on our Site.

We may receive Personally Identifiable Information, as well as “Anonymous Information” (information that is not associated with your Personally Identifiable Information and does not, by itself, permit the identification of individual persons) about you from companies that provide our services by way of a co-branded or private-labeled website or companies that offer their products and/or services on our Site. We may add this information to the information we have already collected from you via our Site in order to improve the services we provide.

We may also collect Personally Identifiable Information at other points in our Site that state that Personally Identifiable Information is being collected. 

If you add guests to your account we will collect information from you about additional guests such as their first and last name in order to facilitate the booking of group purchases. Added guests may contact us at [info@liftopia.com](mailto:info@liftopia.com) to request that we remove this information from our database.

#### How your information is used

The data we gather is used to process your purchase, respond to your requests, contact you if problems arise and, if you have selected to receive them, send you promotional messages. The information we collect helps us to better serve you.

Liftopia uses the information to facilitate the creation of and secure your Account on our network; identify you as a user in our system; provide improved administration of our Site and services; and send you administrative e-mail notifications, such as security or support and maintenance advisories.

Liftopia uses the information that we gather to target content on our Site to more closely match your interests and, if you have selected to receive e-mail communication from us, to target e-mail marketing messages that are more appropriate to your needs.

We may create Anonymous Information from Personally Identifiable Information by excluding information (such as your name) that make the data personally identifiable to you. We use this Anonymous Information to analyze request patterns so that we may enhance the content of our services and improve Site navigation. Liftopia reserves the right to use Anonymous Information for any purpose and disclose Anonymous Information to third parties in its sole discretion.

#### How your information is protected

Liftopia maintains data handling and storage practices and procedures that are designed to ensure the integrity and confidentiality of customer information. The security of your Personally Identifiable Information is important to us. When you enter Personally Identifiable Information (such as your credit card number) on our registration or order forms or we transmit geo location information, we encrypt that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL). We also require you to enter a password to access your Account. Please do not disclose your Account password to unauthorized people. Current Internet security methods and technologies are used to prevent unauthorized access or disclosure, maintain data accuracy and ensure correct use of information.

We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the Personally Identifiable Information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, while we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your Personally Identifiable Information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

If you have any questions about security on our Site, you can send email to us at [info@liftopia.com](mailto:info@liftopia.com). 

#### With whom your information may be shared

When you make a purchase with Liftopia, the Personally Identifiable Information you provide will be shared with the third parties necessary to complete your purchase transaction. For example, we provide your name, address, and phone number to the resort for which you purchased your lift tickets. To charge you for your transaction, we share your name, billing address, and credit card number with the credit card authorization company. Liftopia may also share your Personally Identifiable Information with third party service providers to conduct quality assurance testing, to facilitate the creation of accounts, to provide technical support (including through live chat software) and to provide other services to Liftopia. These third parties are required not to use your Personally Identifiable Information other than to provide the services requested by Liftopia.

We may enter into agreements with companies that provide our products or services by way of a co-branded or private-labeled website or companies that offer their products and/or services on our Site (“Third Party Companies”). A Third Party Company may want access to Personally Identifiable Information that we collect from its customers. As a result, we may disclose your Personally Identifiable Information to a Third Party Company; however, we will not disclose your Personally Identifiable Information to Third Party Companies for the Third Party Companies’ own direct marketing purposes, unless you have “opted-in” by following the instructions we provide to allow such disclosure. If you have opted-in to receive e-mail communications from a Third Party Company and later wish to discontinue receipt of these e-mails, please contact the Third Party Company directly to update your preferences. The privacy policies of our Third Party Companies may apply to the use and disclosure of your Personally Identifiable Information that we collect and disclose to such Third Party Companies. Because we do not control the privacy practices of our Third Party Companies, you should read and understand their privacy policies.

From time to time, we may share Anonymous Information, including general statistical information about our Site and visitors -- such as number of visitors, aggregate and non-personally identifiable demographic data, number and type of goods and services booked, etc. -- with our third-party advertisers and partners. However, we do not reveal your name, address or other Personally Identifiable Information for anything other than the use it was originally intended without giving you the opportunity to opt-out of the disclosure.

Regardless of any choices you make regarding your Personally Identifiable Information (as described below), Liftopia may disclose information about you to others if we have a good faith belief that we are required to do so by law or legal process, to respond to claims, or to protect the rights, property or safety of Liftopia or others. This includes, but is not limited to, customer fraud, technical malfunctions or abuse of our network or systems. We also may provide customer information to third parties, such as credit card companies, for the purpose of resolving disputes that arise in the normal course of business. Except as otherwise stated above, Liftopia will not disclose your Personally Identifiable Information with any third party without your consent.

This Site contains links to other sites that are not owned or controlled by Liftopia. Please be aware that when you click on a link to any other website or location, such as a payment processing site, you will leave our Site and go to another site and another entity may collect Personally Identifiable Information and Anonymous Information from you. Liftopia does not control or review these outside sites or content and is not responsible for the privacy practices of such sites. We encourage you to be aware when you leave our Site and to read the privacy statements of each and every Web site that collects Personally Identifiable Information from you. This Privacy Statement applies only to information collected by this Site.

#### What choices are available?

If your Personally Identifiable Information changes, you may update it by making the change on our My Account section of the Site. You may also send an e-mail to customer support at [support@liftopia.com](mailto:support@liftopia.com) or contact us by telephone or postal mail at the contact information listed at the end of this Privacy Statement. You may request deletion of your Personally Identifiable Information by us, but please note that we may be required to keep this information and not delete it (or to keep this information for a certain time, in which case we will comply with your deletion request only after we have fulfilled such requirements). When we delete any information, it will be deleted from the active database, but may remain in our archives. We may retain your geo location and personal information for fraud or similar purposes as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements. We will respond to your request to access your Personally Identifiable Information within 30 days.

As we explain in more detail below, Liftopia uses cookies to improve your ordering experience and to reduce the time it takes for you to complete a purchase transaction. You may choose not to receive a cookie file by enabling your Web browser to refuse cookies or to prompt you before accepting a cookie. Please be aware, however, that by refusing to accept cookies, you may be unable to access a significant portion of the Site.

#### Cookies

A cookie is a unique identifier sent to your computer by a Web server and stored on your computer's hard drive. A cookie lets a computer server identify your computer. A cookie is what allows many sites to greet you upon every return with a message even before you actively login. At Liftopia, we use cookies to improve your shopping experience, reduce the time it takes for you to complete a purchase transaction, and to serve advertisements as described below. Our cookies do not retrieve any Personally Identifiable Information, but they do help us track which of our Web pages are visited, the date and time of such visit, and what services are most often used. Please note that in order to use our Site, your Web browser must be configured to accept cookies.

The use of cookies by our partners, affiliates, tracking utility company, service providers is not covered by our privacy statement. We do not have access or control over these cookies. Our partners, affiliates, tracking utility company, service providers use both session ID and persistent cookies to help you navigate through our site. 

#### Clear Gifs

We and our third party advertising partners employ a software technology called clear gifs (a.k.a. Web Beacons/Web Bugs), that help us better manage content on our site by informing us what content is effective. Clear gifs are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies, and are used to track the online movements of Web users. In contrast to cookies, which are stored on a user’s computer hard drive, clear gifs are embedded invisibly on Web pages and are about the size of the period at the end of this sentence. We tie the information gathered by clear gifs to our customers’ personally identifiable information. 

We use clear gifs in our HTML-based emails to let us know which emails have been opened by recipients. This allows us to gauge the effectiveness of certain communications and the effectiveness of our marketing campaigns. 

#### Affiliates and Acquisitions

We may share some or all of your Personally Identifiable Information with our parent company, subsidiaries, joint ventures, or other companies under a common control (“Affiliates”), in which case we will require our Affiliates to honor this Privacy Statement. In the event that Liftopia or substantially all of Liftopia's assets are acquired, customer information may be transferred to Liftopia's successor company. In the event such a transfer occurs, your Personally Identifiable Information will be subject to the same protection as it was prior to the transfer.

#### Public Forums

Our web site offers publicly accessible blogs or community forums. You should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them. To request removal of your Personally Identifiable Information from our blog or community forum, contact us at [support@liftopia.com](mailto:support@liftopia.com). In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.

#### Social Media Features and Widgets

Our web site includes social media features, such as the Facebook button and widgets, such as the Share this button or interactive mini-programs that run on our site. These features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. Social media features and widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our site. Your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it. 

#### Advertising

We partner with a third party ad network to either display advertising on our web site or to manage our advertising on other sites. Our ad network partner uses cookies and web beacons to collect non-personally identifiable information about your activities on this and other web sites to provide you targeted advertising based upon your interests. If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you targeted ads, you may opt-out by [clicking here](http://preferences.truste.com/). Please note this does not opt you out of being served advertising. You will continue to receive generic ads.

#### Children

Children are not eligible to make purchases on our Site and we ask that anyone under the age of 13 not submit any Personally Identifiable Information to us. Liftopia does not knowingly collect Personally Identifiable Information from anyone under the age of 13.

#### International Users - Applicable Law

Liftopia collects, processes, stores, discloses and disposes of Personally Identifiable Information that you submit to us in accordance with applicable United States law, which may be less stringent than the laws of your country. Please note that the Personally Identifiable Information you submit to our Site will be transferred to the United States to be processed by Liftopia for the purposes set forth in this Privacy Statement. If you are not a resident of the United States, you acknowledge and agree that we may collect, use and store your Personally Identifiable Information, as discussed in this Privacy Statement, outside of your resident jurisdiction. We adhere to the United States / European Union Data Protection Safe Harbor Arrangement, which can be located at <http://www.export.gov/safeharbor>. 

#### Notification of Changes

This Privacy Statement is subject to occasional revision, and if we make any material changes in the way we use your Personally Identifiable Information, we will notify you by sending you an e-mail to the last e-mail address you provided to us and/or by prominently posting notice of the changes on our Site. Any changes to this Privacy Statement will be effective upon the earlier of thirty (30) calendar days following our dispatch of an e-mail notice to you or thirty (30) calendar days following our posting of notice of the changes on our Site. These changes will be effective immediately for new users of our Site or service. Please note that at all times you are responsible for updating your Personally Identifiable Information to provide us with your most current e-mail address. In the event that the last e-mail address that you have provided us is not valid, or for any reason is not capable of delivering to you the notice described above, our dispatch of the e-mail containing such notice will nonetheless constitute effective notice of the changes described in the notice. In any event, changes to this Privacy Statement may affect our use of Personally Identifiable Information that you provided us prior to our notification to you of the changes. If you do not wish to permit changes in our use of your Personally Identifiable Information, you must notify us prior to the effective date of the changes that you wish to deactivate your Account with us. Continued use of our Site or service, following notice of such changes shall indicate your acknowledgement of such changes and agreement to be bound by the terms and conditions of such changes.

#### Opt Out Opportunity

We provide you the opportunity to "opt-out" of having your Personally Identifiable Information used for certain purposes when we ask for such information. If you no longer wish to receive free newsletters or promotional communications from us, you may opt-out of receiving them by following the instructions included in each communication, by emailing us at [support@liftopia.com](mailto:support@liftopia.com), or by contacting us at (800) 349-0870.

To opt out of push notifications, please go to device settings to turn off notifications. You may opt out of location based services at any time by editing the setting at the device level. 

#### Contact Us

If you have questions or concerns regarding your privacy or security on our Site, feel free to contact us by e-mail, phone or postal mail. Our customer care associates are available to answer your questions or address your concerns.

E-mail: [info@liftopia.com](mailto:info@liftopia.com)  
Phone (toll-free): (800) 349-0870  
Mailing Address:  
Liftopia, Inc.  
731 Market Street  
2nd Floor  
San Francisco CA 94103 U.S.A.
